<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>AvaloniaUI/Avalonia - Releases</title>
  <link href="https://github.com/AvaloniaUI/Avalonia" />
  <updated>2023-07-06T00:06:09Z</updated>
  <id>https://github.com/AvaloniaUI/Avalonia</id>
  <entry>
    <title>AvaloniaUI/Avalonia - Releases - 2023-07-05</title>
    <id>https://github.com/AvaloniaUI/Avalonia#2023-07-05</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AvaloniaUI/Avalonia" />
    <updated>2023-07-06T00:06:09Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
                &lt;div&gt;
                    
                        &lt;article&gt;
                            &lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/AvaloniaUI/Avalonia/releases/tag/11.0.0"&gt;11.0.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;Our docs have had an overhaul also:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://docs.avaloniaui.net/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.avaloniaui.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See this guide on how to update your application.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://docs.avaloniaui.net/docs/next/stay-up-to-date/upgrade-from-0.10" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.avaloniaui.net/docs/next/stay-up-to-date/upgrade-from-0.10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Avalonia/11.0.0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nuget.org/packages/Avalonia/11.0.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A11y (Accessibility)&lt;br&gt;
This version of Avalonia takes major strides in making applications more accessible. We've added support for various accessibility tools, making it easier for everyone to use Avalonia applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IME (Input Method Editor) Support&lt;br&gt;
We have introduced support for Input Method Editor (IME), this allows onscreen keyboards and input in all languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compositing Renderer&lt;br&gt;
The new compositing renderer enhances the graphical rendering capabilities, providing a more robust, efficient, and flexible rendering pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebAssembly (WASM) Support&lt;br&gt;
WASM support allows Avalonia applications to run directly in the browser, broadening our platform support and giving developers more freedom and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS and Android Support&lt;br&gt;
We've added support for both iOS and Android platforms. Developers can now build and run Avalonia applications on two of the most popular mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full Rich Text support&lt;br&gt;
You can now fully render rich text allowing you to render complex documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Text Inlines feature, you can easily construct complex formatted text blocks. It enables you to add annotations, hyperlinks, and other inline elements in your text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smooth Virtualization (Reworked ItemsControl)&lt;br&gt;
We've completely reworked the ItemsControl to provide smooth virtualization. This improves the efficiency and user experience for controls with many items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance Improvements&lt;br&gt;
Avalonia 11.0 comes with significant performance improvements, enhancing the speed and efficiency of your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control Themes, Nested Styles, and Theme Variants&lt;br&gt;
We've added the ability to theme controls, apply nested styles, and choose theme variants. This makes it easier to build beautiful and consistent UIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitmap Effects&lt;br&gt;
The Bitmap Effects feature lets you apply visual effects to bitmaps. You can add blur, drop shadows, and other effects to images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D Transforms&lt;br&gt;
With 3D Transforms, you can now create stunning three-dimensional effects in your UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AOT (Ahead-Of-Time) Compilation and Trimming&lt;br&gt;
AOT compilation enables your apps to run faster by compiling them before runtime. Trimming reduces the size of your apps by removing unused code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPU Interop&lt;br&gt;
The GPU Interop feature allows Avalonia to work more efficiently with the GPU, improving rendering performance and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental Metal Support&lt;br&gt;
We're testing Metal support to improve performance on iOS and macOS devices.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/article&gt;
                    
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </content>
  </entry>
</feed>